<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Shielding Stories on The Shielding</title><link>https://shielding.world/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Shielding Stories on The Shielding</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shielding.world/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>People like us don't go to the Houses of Parliament on a tractor</title><link>https://shielding.world/posts/name-people-like-us-dont-go-to-the-houses-of-parliament-on-a-tractor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shielding.world/posts/name-people-like-us-dont-go-to-the-houses-of-parliament-on-a-tractor/</guid><description>I am scientifically educated myself, but funnily enough, it was through my son that I learned about the new coronavirus very early on.1 He has friends from all over the world, so he heard rumours in December 2019 that something was off. At first I thought it would be okay. With SARS-CoV-1 it also ended with a sizzle. But then in January it started to become very clear, and it was my son who first concluded: mom, this is going wrong.</description></item><item><title>Consciously keeping distance</title><link>https://shielding.world/posts/anohni-consciously-keeping-distance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shielding.world/posts/anohni-consciously-keeping-distance/</guid><description>At the beginning of the pandemic, even before the first lockdown, I was approached on the street by a man in Amsterdam, who seemed to be working out at the gym regularly.1 He took issue with me wearing a face mask, and said that face masks made no sense at all. I felt I had to counter it right away. I told him that a grandchild was on the way, and that I would like to see them grow up.</description></item><item><title>Someone else shouldn't be allowed to decide whether I get ill</title><link>https://shielding.world/posts/sophie-someone-else-shouldnt-be-allowed-to-decide-whether-i-get-ill/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shielding.world/posts/sophie-someone-else-shouldnt-be-allowed-to-decide-whether-i-get-ill/</guid><description>In March 2020 my partner fell out with a colleague at work who was coughing violently and who wasn&amp;rsquo;t following the government advice already in force at the time, namely to stay at home if you had any symptoms1. He then went to HR, where people still doubted whether they should do anything with the situation. At that time, we were following all the international news about Wuhan and Italy. About several things we remember saying to each other: &amp;lsquo;Enjoy it now, because this is going to get serious&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>The risk of chronic damage is getting closer</title><link>https://shielding.world/posts/helen-the-risk-of-chronic-damage-is-getting-closer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shielding.world/posts/helen-the-risk-of-chronic-damage-is-getting-closer/</guid><description>In January 2020 I read in a newspaper about the coronavirus in China and was immediately alert.1 I started reading up on it. The first reports I came across from China were confusing and disturbing. Within a few days, my alertness grew into worry and real stress. I sensed that this was going to disrupt everything soon, unless we took action. I tried to discuss it with others, but almost everyone brushed it off.</description></item><item><title>Resistance to mass fantasy</title><link>https://shielding.world/posts/daan-resistance-to-a-mass-fantasy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shielding.world/posts/daan-resistance-to-a-mass-fantasy/</guid><description>Four years ago I had a conversation with a colleague about ‘the pandemic that was going to happen soon’.1 They worked in veterinary science and studied avian influenza. Back then, the scientific community seemed convinced that a ‘flu would be the culprit of the next worldwide outbreak. The damage would likely be considerable, my colleague told me. A death rate of 2% would end society as we know it, I was told, but even a less severe virus would be enough for a transformative moment.</description></item><item><title>I still don’t dare look far into the future</title><link>https://shielding.world/posts/johanna-I-still-dont-date-look-far-into-the-future/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shielding.world/posts/johanna-I-still-dont-date-look-far-into-the-future/</guid><description>I retired just before the pandemic started.1 That had been quite a turning point for me. I had worked in education until I turned 66. All my life I have been in front of the classroom and was I able to help children and my colleagues. I have always had the feeling that I was really doing something for society. And I would have wanted to continue working, but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t allowed.</description></item><item><title>If this can’t push people into action, what will?</title><link>https://shielding.world/posts/joan-if-this-cant-push-people-into-action/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shielding.world/posts/joan-if-this-cant-push-people-into-action/</guid><description>We had recently moved to Tasmania from New South Wales, and had built a house in Southern Tasmania when the pandemic began.1 Frank, my husband, works remotely from his office, which is based in Sydney. We used to return to Sydney every six months or so, so that he could go into the office and we could visit our friends. Our daughter had started kindergarten at school, and my son was starting to be old enough to take part in activities such as kindergym.</description></item><item><title>A principled, completely rational and moral decision</title><link>https://shielding.world/posts/guus-a-principled-completely-rational-moral-decision/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://shielding.world/posts/guus-a-principled-completely-rational-moral-decision/</guid><description>The initial decision to shield for me came based on the reports that we were getting from China (mostly through Twitter and personal contacts at this point) about people experiencing severe pneumonia, breathing difficulties and deaths.1 Li Wenliang, the doctor who had initially rang the alarm over a new SARS-like disease, had also sadly died at this point.
I realized that this was a new, unknown virus. I also realized that we had no clue about the sort and extent of health damage that this might cause.</description></item></channel></rss>