<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Docs on The Shielding</title>
    <link>https://shielding.world/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Docs on The Shielding</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://shielding.world/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Worksheet</title>
      <link>https://shielding.world/docs/worksheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shielding.world/docs/worksheet/</guid>
      <description>Worksheet #  Use the prompts from this worksheet to write about your own life while shielding, or to interview someone else about their story.
Would you like to share your story at The Shielding (anonymously)? We&amp;rsquo;d love to hear from you! You can reach us at: theshielding@protonmail.com.
Download worksheet as PDF (17 KB)
Download worksheet as plain text (1 KB)
Worksheet #  Basics #   How would you describe your circumstances before the pandemic?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Part</title>
      <link>https://shielding.world/docs/take-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shielding.world/docs/take-part/</guid>
      <description>Take Part #  Are you, or have you been, shielding? Or maybe you know someone who shields? If so, we would love to hear from you! Anonymous stories are welcome.
Fill out the form below, and we&amp;rsquo;ll be in touch.
Name (pseudonym fine):  Email:  What interview format would you prefer? Select Email Video call Call (no video)   Could you say a few words about your shielding?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://shielding.world/docs/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shielding.world/docs/about/</guid>
      <description>About #  The Shielding is run by a small group of people with one thing in common: all of us have been shielding since early on in the current COVID-19 pandemic.
We started The Shielding in March 2022 out of a sense of bafflement and urgency.
Bafflement, because it seemed that the outside world had fallen largely into pandemic denialism. Even though in many regions, infections numbers are still intolerably high.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
